Brandon Hernández

Career Summary

Brandon is a committed and enthusiastic data scientist and software developer with experience in machine learning and data engineering. 5+ years programming with Python and Java, also experience developing APIs using FastAPI. Knowledge about NLP, Computer vision, data analysis, and data visualization.

Summary of Qualifications

Proficient In:

- Python
- Machine learning
- NLP

- Computer vision
- Databases
- SQL

- Serverless framework
- Cloud tools
- APIs

Data visualization

Jul. 2021 – present

- Docker
- Git

Languages

• Spanish (native speaker)

English (advanced)

Career History

Globant, Mexico City, Mexico

Python developer / Data architect

- Development of applications for data ingestion and process optimization
- Use of snowflake features to setup the data ingestion and data processing
- Use of serverless framework for application deployment
- Development of AWS Lambdas and Step functions for process automation

LISA Insurtech, Chile

Jan. 2021 - Jul. 2021

Data scientist and developer

- Development of APIs to settle claims using FastAPI and Python
- Development of NLP Machine learning models with SpaCy to classify and extract data
- Deployment of Elasticsearch databases to store and analyze data
- Development of Datadog dashboards for metric analysis
- Use of AWS and GCP microservices

Procter & Gamble, Mexico City, Mexico

Jul. 2020 – Dec. 2020

Digitization intern

- Creation of dashboards for data analysis and process optimization
- Development of applications for TI needs (enter registration, COVID questionary, alerts update)
- Development of computer vision systems to detect unhealthy products in production lines

Achievements and personal projects

- Co-author of A Case-Based approach to Creating Movie Posters Compositions, published full paper for International Conference on Computational Creativity (2021) Available clicking here.
- Thesis project: Design and implementation of a robotic system with artificial vision applied to litter detection in shallow low-light waters.
- Summer research at University of California San Diego developing computer vision models (2019)

Education

Mexican Autonomous Institute of Technology (ITAM), Mexico City, Mexico Aug. 2015 – Dec. 2020 BS, Telecommunications Engineering and BS, Mechatronics Engineering